<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Your Blog Name</title>
	<subtitle>I am writing about my experiences as a naval navel-gazer.</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://myurl.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://myurl.com/"/>
	<updated>2018-10-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://myurl.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Your Name Here</name>
		<email>youremailaddress@example.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Golden Apple Tree and the Nine Peahens -- The Witch</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/golden-apple-tree-part-4/"/>
		<updated>2018-10-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/golden-apple-tree-part-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Next day, when the dragon went out, the king&#39;s son came, and the queen told him all she had learned from the dragon. Then the king&#39;s son went away to the mountain and found the old woman, and entered her house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She greeted, &amp;quot;God help you too, my son! What do you wish?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I should like to serve you,&amp;quot; said the king&#39;s son. Then the old woman said, &amp;quot;Well, my son, if you keep my mare safe for three days and three nights, I will give you the best horse, and you can choose him yourself. But if you do not keep the mare safe, you shall lose your head.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then she led him into the courtyard, where all around stakes were ranged. Each of them had on it a man&#39;s head, except one stake, which had no head on it, and shouted incessantly, &amp;quot;Oh, grandmother, give me a head!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old woman showed all this to the prince, and said, &amp;quot;Look here! All these were heads of those who tried to keep my mare, and they have lost their heads for their pains!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the prince was not a bit afraid, so he stayed to serve the old woman. When the evening came he mounted the mare and rode her into the field, and the foal followed. He sat still on her back, having made up his mind not to dismount, that he might be sure of her. But before midnight he slumbered a little, and when he awoke he found himself sitting on a rail and holding the bridle in his hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he was greatly alarmed, and went instantly to look about to find the mare, and whilst looking for her, he came to a piece of water. When he saw the water he remembered the little fish, and took the scale from the handkerchief and rubbed it a little. Then immediately the little fish appeared and said, &amp;quot;What is the matter, my half-brother?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he replied, &amp;quot;The mare of the old woman ran away whilst under my charge, and now I do not know where she is!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the fish answered, &amp;quot;Here she is, turned to a fish, and the foal to a smaller one. But strike once upon the water with the bridle and cry out, &#39;Hey! mare of the old woman!&#39;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prince did as he was told, and immediately the mare came, with the foal, out of the water to the shore. Then he put on her the bridle and mounted and rode away to the old woman&#39;s house, and the foal followed. When he got there the old woman gave him his breakfast. She, however, took the mare into the stable and beat her with a poker, saying, &amp;quot;Why did you not go down among the fishes, you cursed mare?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the mare answered, &amp;quot;I have been down to the fishes, but the fish are his friends, and they told him about me.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the old woman said, &amp;quot;Then go among the foxes!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When evening came the king&#39;s son mounted the mare and rode to the field, and the foal followed the mare. Again he sat on the mare&#39;s back until near midnight, when he fell asleep as before. When he awoke, he found himself riding on the rail and holding the bridle in his hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So he was much frightened, and went to look after the mare. As he went, he remembered the words the old woman had said to the mare, and he took from the handkerchief the fox&#39;s hair and rubbed it a little between his fingers. All at once the fox stood before him, and asked, &amp;quot;What is the matter, half-brother?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he said, &amp;quot;The old woman&#39;s mare has run away, and I do not know where she can be.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the fox answered, &amp;quot;Here she is with us. She has turned into a fox, and the foal into a cub. But strike once with the bridle on the earth and cry out, &#39;Hey! you old woman&#39;s mare!&#39;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the king&#39;s son struck with the bridle on the earth and cried, &amp;quot;Hey! old woman&#39;s mare!&amp;quot; and the mare came and stood, with her foal, near him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He put on the bridle, and mounted and rode off home, and the foal followed the mare. When he arrived the old woman gave him his breakfast, but took the mare into the stable and beat her with the poker, crying, &amp;quot;To the foxes, cursed one! To the foxes!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the mare answered, &amp;quot;I have been with the foxes, but they are his friends, and told him I was there!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the old woman cried, &amp;quot;If that is so, you must go among the wolves!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it grew dark again, the king&#39;s son mounted the mare and rode out to the field, and the foal galloped by the side of the mare. Again he sat still on the mare&#39;s back till about midnight, when he grew very sleepy and fell into a slumber, as on the former evenings, and when he awoke he found himself riding on the rail, holding the bridle in his hand, just as before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, as before, he went in a hurry to look after the mare. As he went, he remembered the words the old woman had said to the mare, and took the wolf&#39;s hair from the handkerchief and rubbed it a little. Then the wolf came up to him and asked, &amp;quot;What is the matter, half-brother?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he answered, &amp;quot;The old woman&#39;s mare has run away, and I cannot tell where she is.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wolf said, &amp;quot;Here she is with us. She has turned herself into a wolf, and the foal into a wolf&#39;s cub. Strike once with the bridle on the earth and cry out, &#39;Hey! old woman&#39;s mare!&#39;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the king&#39;s son did so, and instantly the mare came again and stood with the foal beside him. So he bridled her, and galloped home, and the foal followed. When he arrived the old woman gave him his breakfast, but she led the mare into the stable and beat her with the poker, crying, &amp;quot;To the wolves, I said, miserable one!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the mare answered, &amp;quot;I have been to the wolves, but they are his friends, and told him all about me!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the old woman came out of the stable, and the king&#39;s son said to her, &amp;quot;Eh! grandmother, I have served you honestly. Now give me what you promised me.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the old woman answered, &amp;quot;My son, what is promised must be fulfilled. So look here. Here are the twelve horses. Choose which you like!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the prince said, &amp;quot;Why should I be too particular? Give me only that leprous horse in the corner! Fine horses are not fitting for me!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the old woman tried to persuade him to choose another horse, saying, &amp;quot;How can you be so foolish as to choose that leprous thing whilst there are such very fine horses here?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he remained firm by his first choice, and said to the old woman, &amp;quot;You ought to give me which I choose, for so you promised.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when the old woman found she could not make him change his mind, she gave him the scabby horse, and he took leave of her, and went away, leading the horse by the halter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he came to a forest he curried and rubbed down the horse, when it shone as bright as gold. He then mounted, and the horse flew as quickly as a bird, and in a few seconds brought him to the dragon&#39;s palace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The king&#39;s son went in and said to the queen, &amp;quot;Get ready as soon as possible!&amp;quot; She was soon ready, when they both mounted the horse, and began their journey home. Soon after, the dragon came home, and when he saw the queen had disappeared, said to his horse, &amp;quot;What shall we do? Shall we eat and drink first, or shall we pursue them at once?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The horse answered, &amp;quot;Whether we eat and drink or not, it is all one. We shall never reach them.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the dragon heard that, he got quickly on his horse and galloped after them. When they saw the dragon following them, they pushed on quicker, but their horse said, &amp;quot;Do not be afraid! There is no need to run away.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a very few moments the dragon came very near to them, and his horse said to their horse, &amp;quot;For God&#39;s sake, my brother, wait a moment! I shall kill myself running after you!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their horse answered, &amp;quot;Why are you so stupid as to carry that monster? Fling your heels up and throw him off, and come along with me!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the dragon&#39;s horse heard that, he shook his head angrily and flung his feet high in the air, so that the dragon fell off and brake in pieces, and his horse came up to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the queen mounted him and returned with the king&#39;s son happily to her kingdom, where they reigned together in great prosperity until the day of their death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source&lt;/em&gt;: Csedomille Mijatovies, &lt;em&gt;Serbian Folk-Lore: Popular Tales&lt;/em&gt; (London: W.Isbister and Company, 1874), pp. 43-58. Taken from here: https://sites.pitt.edu/~dash/swan.html&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Golden Apple Tree and the Nine Peahens -- The Dragon</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/golden-apple-tree-part-3/"/>
		<updated>2018-10-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/golden-apple-tree-part-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So next morning the king&#39;s son arose, and prepared to go. He thanked the hermit, and went as he had told him. After a while he came to the great gate, and, having passed it, turned to the right, so that at midday he saw the city, and beholding how white it shone, rejoiced very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he came into the city he found the palace where lived the nine golden peahens. But at the gate he was stopped by the guard, who demanded who he was, and whence he came. After he had answered these questions, the guards went to announce him to the queen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the queen heard who he was, she came running out to the gate and took him by the hand to lead him into the palace. She was a young and beautiful maiden, and so there was a great rejoicing when, after a few days, he married her and remained there with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, some time after their marriage, the queen went out to walk, and the king&#39;s son remained in the palace. Before going out, however, the queen gave him the keys of twelve cellars, telling him, &amp;quot;You may go down into all the cellars except the twelfth -- that must on no account open, or it will cost you your head.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She then went away. The king&#39;s son whilst remaining in the palace began to wonder what there could be in the twelfth cellar, and soon commenced opening one cellar after the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he came to the twelfth he would not at first open it, but again began to wonder very much why he was forbidden to go into it. &amp;quot;What can be in this cellar?&amp;quot; he exclaimed to himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last he opened it. In the middle of the cellar lay a big barrel with an open bung-hole, but bound fast round with three iron hoops. Out of the barrel came a voice, saying, &amp;quot;For God&#39;s sake, my brother, I am dying with thirst. Please give me a cup of water!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the king&#39;s son took a cup and filled it with water, and emptied it into the barrel. Immediately he had done so, one of the hoops burst asunder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again came the voice from the barrel, &amp;quot;For God&#39;s sake, my brother, I am dying of thirst. Please give me a cup of water!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The king&#39;s son again filled the cup, and took it, and emptied it into the barrel, and instantly another hoop burst asunder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third time the voice came out of the barrel, &amp;quot;For God&#39;s sake, my brother, I am dying of thirst. Please give me a cup of water!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The king&#39;s son again took the cup and filled it, and poured the water into the barrel, and the third hoop burst. Then the barrel fell to pieces, and a dragon flew out of the cellar, and caught the queen on the road and carried her away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the servant, who went out with the queen, came back quickly, and told the king&#39;s son what had happened, and the poor prince knew not what to do with himself, so desperate was he, and full of self reproaches. At length, however, he resolved to set out and travel through the world in search of her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After long journeying, one day he came to a lake, and near it, in a little hole, he saw a little fish jumping about. When the fish saw the king&#39;s son, she began to beg pitifully, &amp;quot;For God&#39;s sake, be my brother, and throw me into the water. Some day I may be of use to you, so take now a little scale from me, and when you need me, rub it gently.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the king&#39;s son lifted the little fish from the hole and threw her into the water, after he had taken one small scale, which he wrapped up carefully in a handkerchief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time afterwards, as he traveled about the world, he came upon a fox, caught in an iron trap. When the fox saw the prince, he spoke, &amp;quot;In God&#39;s name, be a brother to me, and help me to get out of this trap. One day you will need me, so take just one hair from my tail, and when you want me, rub it gently.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the king&#39;s son took a hair from the tail of the fox, and let him free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, as he crossed a mountain, he found a wolf fast in a trap; and when the wolf saw him, it spoke, &amp;quot;Be a brother to me. In God&#39;s name, set me free, and one day I will help you. Only take a hair from me, and when you need me, rub it gently.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So he took a hair, and let the wolf free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, the king&#39;s son traveled about a very long time, till one day he met a man, to whom he said, &amp;quot;For God&#39;s sake, brother, have you ever heard anyone say where is the palace of the dragon king?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The man gave him very particular directions which way to take, and in what length of time he could get there. Then the king&#39;s son thanked him and continued his journey until he came to the city where the dragon lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When there, he went into the palace and found therein his wife, and both of them were exceedingly pleased to meet each other, and began to take counsel how they could escape. They resolved to run away, and prepared hastily for the journey. When all was ready they mounted on horseback and galloped away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as they were gone, the dragon came home, also on horseback, and, entering his palace, found that the queen had gone away. Then he said to his horse, &amp;quot;What shall we do now? Shall we eat and drink, or go at once after them?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The horse answered, &amp;quot;Let us eat and drink first. We shall anyway catch them. Do not be anxious.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the dragon had dined, he mounted his horse, and in a few moments came up with the runaways. Then he took the queen from the king&#39;s son and said to him, &amp;quot;Go now, in God&#39;s name! This time I forgive you, because you gave me water in the cellar. But if your life is dear to you, do not come back here any more!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unhappy young prince went on his way a little, but could not long resist, so he came back next day to the dragon&#39;s palace, and found the queen sitting alone and weeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then they began again to consult how they could get away. And the prince said, &amp;quot;When the dragon comes, ask him where he got that horse, and then you will tell me so that I can look for such another one; perhaps in this way we can escape.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He then went away, lest the dragon should come and find him with the queen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By and by the dragon came home, and the queen began to pet him, and speak lovingly to him about many things, till at last she said, &amp;quot;Ah! what a fine horse you have! Where did you get such a splendid horse?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he answered, &amp;quot;Eh! Where I got it everyone cannot get one! In such and such a mountain lives an old woman who has twelve horses in her stable, and no one can say which is the finest, they are all so beautiful. But in one corner of the stable stands a horse which looks as if he were leprous, but, in truth, he is the very best horse in the whole world. He is the brother of my horse, and whoever gets him may ride to the sky. But whoever wishes to get a horse from that old woman, must serve her three days and three nights. She has a mare with a foal, and whoever during three nights guards and keeps for her this mare and this foal, has a right to claim the best horse from the old woman&#39;s stable. But whoever engages to keep watch over the mare and does not, must lose his head!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Golden Apple Tree and the Nine Peahens -- The Search</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/golden-apple-tree-part-2/"/>
		<updated>2018-10-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/golden-apple-tree-part-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At length he resolved to go and look after his peahen; resolving never to come back again unless he should find her. When he told the king his father of his intention, the king begged him not do go away, and told him that he would find him another beautiful girl, and that he might choose out of the whole kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But all the king&#39;s persuasions were useless, so his son went into the world -- taking only one servant to serve him -- to search everywhere for his peahen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many travels he came one day to a lake. Now by the lake stood a large and beautiful palace. In the palace lived an old woman as queen, and with the queen lived a girl, her daughter. He said to the old woman, &amp;quot;For heaven&#39;s sake, grandmother, do you know anything about nine golden peahens?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the old woman answered, &amp;quot;Oh, my son, I know all about them. They come every midday to bathe in the lake. But what do you want with them? Let them be. Think nothing about them. Here is my daughter. Such a beautiful girl! And such an heiress! All my wealth will remain to you if you marry her.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he, burning with desire to see the peahens, would not listen to what the old woman spoke about her daughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next morning, when day dawned, the prince prepared to go down to the lake to wait for the peahens. Then the old queen bribed the servant and gave him a little pair of bellows, and said, &amp;quot;Do you see these bellows? When you come to the lake you must blow secretly with them behind his neck, and then he will fall asleep, and not be able to speak to the peahens.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mischievous servant did as the old woman told him. When he went with his master down to the lake, he took occasion to blow with the bellows behind his neck, and the poor prince fell asleep just as though he were dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after, the nine peahens came flying, and eight of them alighted by the lake, but the ninth flew towards him as he sat on horseback, and caressed him, and tried to awaken him. &amp;quot;Awake my darling! Awake, my heart! Awake, my soul!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for all that he knew nothing, just as if he were dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After they had bathed, all the peahens flew away together, and after they were gone the prince woke up, and said to his servant, &amp;quot;What has happened? Did they not come?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The servant told him they had been there, and that eight of them had bathed, but the ninth had sat by him on his horse, and caressed and tried to awaken him. Then the king&#39;s son was so angry that he almost killed himself in his rage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next morning he went down again to the shore to wait for the peahens, and rode about a long time till the servant again found an opportunity of blowing with the bellows behind his neck, so that he again fell asleep as though dead. Hardly had he fallen asleep before the nine peahens came flying, and eight of them alighted by the water, but the ninth settled down by the side of his horse and caressed him, and cried out to awaken him, &amp;quot;Arise, my darling! Arise, my heart! Arise my soul!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was of no use. The prince slept on as if he were dead. Then she said to the servant, &amp;quot;Tell your master, tomorrow he can see us here again, but nevermore.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these words the peahens flew away. Immediately after, the king&#39;s son woke up and asked his servant, &amp;quot;Have they not been here?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the man answered, &amp;quot;Yes, they have been, and say that you can see them again tomorrow, at this place, but after that they will not return again.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the unhappy prince heard that, he knew not what to do with himself, and in his great trouble and misery tore the hair from his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third day he went down again to the shore, but, fearing to fall asleep, instead of riding slowly, galloped along the shore. His servant, however, found an opportunity of blowing with the bellows behind his neck, and again the prince fell asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A moment after came the nine peahens, and the eight alighted on the lake and the ninth by him on his horse, and sought to awaken him, caressing him. &amp;quot;Arise, my darling! Arise, my heart! Arise, my soul!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was of no use. He slept on as if dead. Then the peahen said to the servant, &amp;quot;When your master awakens tell him he ought to strike off the head of the nail from the lower part, and then he will find me.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thereupon all the peahens fled away. Immediately the king&#39;s son awoke and said to his servant, &amp;quot;Have they been here?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the servant answered, &amp;quot;They have been, and the one which alighted on your horse, ordered me to tell you to strike off the head of the nail from the lower part, and then you will find her.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the prince heard that, he drew his sword and cut off his servant&#39;s head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that he traveled alone about the world, and, after long traveling, came to a mountain and remained all night there with a hermit, whom he asked if he knew anything about nine golden peahens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hermit said, &amp;quot;Eh! My son, you are lucky. God has led you in the right path. From this place it is only a half a day&#39;s walk. But you must go straight on, then you will come to a large gate, which you must pass through. And, after that, you must keep always to the right hand, and so you will come to the peahens&#39; city, and there find their palace.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Golden Apple Tree and the Nine Peahens, Part I</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/golden-apple-tree-part-1/"/>
		<updated>2018-10-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/golden-apple-tree-part-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our next theme concerns what I shall tongue-in-cheek refer to as &amp;quot;wif-swans&amp;quot;: Woman-swans, or wife-swans. Because the Old English word for &lt;em&gt;woman&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;wif&lt;/em&gt;, and this is relevant because the Old English word for &lt;em&gt;man&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;wer&lt;/em&gt;, from which we derive &lt;em&gt;werewolf&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;weregild&lt;/em&gt; (man-price, blood money). This particular version comes from Serbia, only they switch it up by using peahens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://myurl.com/assets/img/wlop-black-swan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;woman in a fancy dress reads a book in a bright ballroom, while swans cavort about her&quot; style=&quot;max-width:85vh;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Black Swan by WLOP /&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artstation.com/artwork/ZGr13N&quot;&gt; Art Station&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-golden-apple-tree-and-the-nine-peahens-part-i&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The Golden Apple Tree and the Nine Peahens, Part I &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://myurl.com/golden-apple-tree-part-1/#the-golden-apple-tree-and-the-nine-peahens-part-i&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time there lived a king who had three sons. Now, before the king&#39;s palace grew a golden apple tree, which in one and the same night blossomed, bore fruit, and lost all its fruit, though no one could tell who took the apples. One day the king, speaking to his eldest son, said, &amp;quot;I should like to know who takes the fruit from our apple tree!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the son said, &amp;quot;I will keep guard tonight, and will see who gathers the apples.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when the evening came he went and laid himself down, under the apple tree, upon the ground to watch. Just, however, as the apples ripened, he fell asleep, and when he awoke in the morning, there was not a single one left on the tree. Whereupon he went and told his father what had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the second son offered to keep watch by the tree, but he had no better success than his eldest brother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the turn came to the king&#39;s youngest son to keep guard. He made his preparations, brought his bed under the tree, and immediately went to sleep. Before midnight he awoke and looked up at the tree, and saw how the apples ripened, and how the whole palace was lit up by their shining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that minute nine peahens flew towards the tree, and eight of them settled on its branches, but the ninth alighted near him and turned instantly into a beautiful girl -- so beautiful, indeed, that the whole kingdom could not produce one who could in any way compare with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She stayed, conversing kindly with him, till after midnight, then thanking him for the golden apples, she prepared to depart. But, as he begged she would leave him one, she gave him two, one for himself and one for the king his father. Then the girl turned again into a peahen, and flew away with the other eight. Next morning, the king&#39;s son took the two apples to his father, and the king was much pleased, and praised his son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the evening came, the king&#39;s youngest son took his place again under the apple tree to keep guard over it. He again conversed as he had done the night before with the beautiful girl, and brought to his father, the next morning, two apples as before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, after he had succeeded so well several nights, his two elder brothers grew envious because he had been able to do what they could not. At length they found an old woman, who promised to discover how the youngest brother had succeeded in saving the two apples. So, as the evening came, the old woman stole softly under the bed which stood under the apple tree, and hid herself. And after a while, came also the king&#39;s son, and laid himself down as usual to sleep. When it was near midnight the nine peahens flew up as before, and eight of them settled on the branches, and the ninth stood by his bed, and turned into a most beautiful girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the old woman slowly took hold of one of the girl&#39;s curls, and cut it off, and the girl immediately rose up, changed again into a peahen and flew away, and the other peahens followed her, and so they all disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the king&#39;s son jumped up, and cried out, &amp;quot;What is that?&amp;quot; and, looking under the bed, he saw the old woman, and drew her out. Next morning he order her to be tied to a horse&#39;s tail, and so torn to pieces. But the peahens never came back, so the king&#39;s son was very sad for a long time, and wept at his loss.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Evil Husbands &amp; Their Curious Wives -- The Devil</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/the-devil/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/the-devil/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our series concludes with a variant of Bluebeard from Venice, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-the-devil-married-three-sisters&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;How the Devil Married Three Sisters &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://myurl.com/the-devil/#how-the-devil-married-three-sisters&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time the devil was seized with a desire to marry. He therefore left hell, took the form of a handsome young man, and built a fine large house. When it was completed and furnished in the most fashionable style he introduced himself to a family where there were three pretty daughters, and paid his addresses to the eldest of them. The handsome man pleased the maiden, her parents were glad to see a daughter so well provided for, and it was not long before the wedding was celebrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he had taken his bride home, he presented her with a very tastefully arranged bouquet, led her through all the rooms of the house, and finally to a closed door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The whole house is at your disposal,&amp;quot; said he, &amp;quot;only I must request one thing of you; that is, that you do not on any account open this door.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the young wife promised faithfully; but equally, of course, she could scarcely wait for the moment to come when she might break her promise. When the devil had left the house the next morning, under pretence of going hunting, she ran hastily to the forbidden door, opened it, and saw a terrible abyss full of fire that shot up towards her, and singed the flowers on her bosom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When her husband came home and asked her whether she had kept her promise, she unhesitatingly said &amp;quot;Yes.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he saw by the flowers that she was telling a lie, and said, &amp;quot;Now I will not put your curiosity to the test any longer. Come with me. I will show you myself what is behind the door.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thereupon he led her to the door, opened it, gave her such a push that she fell down into hell, and shut the door again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months after he wooed the next sister for his wife, and won her; but with her everything that had happened with the first wife was exactly repeated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally he courted the third sister. She was a prudent maiden, and said to herself, &amp;quot;He has certainly murdered my two sisters; but then it is a splendid match for me, so I will try and see whether I cannot be more fortunate than they.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And accordingly she consented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the wedding the bridegroom gave her a beautiful bouquet, but forbade her, also, to open the door which he pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a whit less curious than her sisters, she, too, opened the forbidden door when the devil had gone hunting, but she had previously put her flowers in water. Then she saw behind the door the fatal abyss and her sisters therein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Ah!&amp;quot; she exclaimed, &amp;quot;poor creature that I am; I thought I had married an ordinary man, and instead of that he is the devil! How can I get away from him?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She carefully pulled her two sisters out of hell and hid them. When the devil came home he immediately looked at the bouquet, which she again wore on her bosom, and when he found the flowers so fresh he asked no questions; but reassured as to his secret, he now, for the first time, really loved her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few days she asked him if he would carry three chests for her to her parents&#39; house, without putting them down or resting on the way. &amp;quot;But,&amp;quot; she added, &amp;quot;you must keep your word, for I shall be watching you.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The devil promised to do exactly as she wished. So the next morning she put one of her sisters in a chest, and laid it on her husband&#39;s shoulders. The devil, who is very strong, but also very lazy and unaccustomed to work, soon got tired of carrying the heavy chest, and wanted to rest before he was out of the street on which he lived; but his wife called out to him, &amp;quot;Don&#39;t put it down; I see you!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The devil went reluctantly on with the chest until he had turned the corner, and then said to himself, &amp;quot;She cannot see me here; I will rest a little.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But scarcely had he begun to put the chest down when the sister inside cried out, &amp;quot;Don&#39;t put it down; I see you still!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cursing, he dragged the chest on into another street, and was going to lay it down on a doorstep, but he again heard the voice, &amp;quot;Don&#39;t lay it down, you rascal; I see you still!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What kind of eyes must my wife have,&amp;quot; he thought, &amp;quot;to see around corners as well as straight ahead, and through walls as if they were made of glass!&amp;quot; and thus thinking he arrived, all in a perspiration and quite tired out, at the house of his mother-in-law, to whom he hastily delivered the chest, and then hurried home to strengthen himself with a good breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same thing was repeated the next day with the second chest. On the third day she herself was to be taken home in the chest. She therefore prepared a figure which she dressed in her own clothes, and placed on the balcony, under the pretext of being able to watch him better; slipped quickly into the chest, and had the maid put it on the devil&#39;s back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The deuce!&amp;quot; said he; &amp;quot;this chest is a great deal heavier than the others; and today, when she is sitting on the balcony, I shall have so much the less chance to rest.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So by dint of the greatest exertions he carried it, without stopping, to his mother-in-law, and then hastened home to breakfast, scolding, and with his back almost broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But quite contrary to custom, his wife did not come out to meet him, and there was no breakfast ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Margerita, where are you?&amp;quot; he cried, but received no answer. As he was running through the corridors, he at length looked out of a window and saw the figure on the balcony. &amp;quot;Margerita, have you gone to sleep? Come down. I am as tired as a dog, and as hungry as a wolf.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there was no reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;If you do not come down instantly I will go up and bring you down,&amp;quot; he cried, angrily; but Margerita did not stir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enraged, he hastened up to the balcony, and gave her such a box on the ear that her head flew off, and he saw that the head was nothing but a milliner&#39;s form, and the body, a bundle of rags. Raging, he rushed down and rummaged through the whole house, but in vain; he found only his wife&#39;s empty jewel box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Ha!&amp;quot; he cried; &amp;quot;she has been stolen from me and her jewels, too!&amp;quot; and he immediately ran to inform her parents of the misfortune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when he came near the house, to his great surprise he saw on the balcony above the door all three sisters, his wives, who were looking down on him with scornful laughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three wives at once terrified the devil so much that he took his flight with all possible speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since that time he has lost his taste for marrying.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Evil Husbands &amp; Their Curious Wives -- Fitcher&#39;s Bird</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/fitchers-bird/"/>
		<updated>2018-07-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/fitchers-bird/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Brothers Grimm also shared stories in our theme of &amp;quot;Evil Husbands and Their Curious Wives.&amp;quot; This one is called &amp;quot;Fitcher&#39;s Bird&amp;quot; in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fitcher-s-bird&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Fitcher&#39;s Bird &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://myurl.com/fitchers-bird/#fitcher-s-bird&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://myurl.com/blog/firstpost/&quot;&gt;First post&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://myurl.com/blog/thirdpost/&quot;&gt;Third post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was once a wizard who used to take the form of a poor man, and went to houses and begged, and caught pretty girls. No one knew whither he carried them, for they were never seen more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day he appeared before the door of a man who had three pretty daughters; he looked like a poor weak beggar, and carried a basket on his back, as if he meant to collect charitable gifts in it. He begged for a little food, and when the eldest daughter came out and was just reaching him a piece of bread, he did but touch her, and she was forced to jump into his basket. Thereupon he hurried away with long strides, and carried her away into a dark forest to his house, which stood in the midst of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything in the house was magnificent; he gave her whatsoever she could possibly desire, and said, “My darling, thou wilt certainly be happy with me, for thou hast everything thy heart can wish for.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lasted a few days, and then he said, “I must journey forth, and leave thee alone for a short time; there are the keys of the house; thou mayst go everywhere and look at everything except into one room, which this little key here opens, and there I forbid thee to go on pain of death.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He likewise gave her an egg and said, “Preserve the egg carefully for me, and carry it continually about with thee, for a great misfortune would arise from the loss of it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She took the keys and the egg, and promised to obey him in everything. When he was gone, she went all round the house from the bottom to the top, and examined everything. The rooms shone with silver and gold, and she thought she had never seen such great splendour. At length she came to the forbidden door; she wished to pass it by, but curiosity let her have no rest. She examined the key, it looked just like any other; she put it in the keyhole and turned it a little, and the door sprang open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what did she see when she went in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great bloody basin stood in the middle of the room, and therein lay human beings, dead and hewn to pieces, and hard by was a block of wood, and a gleaming axe lay upon it. She was so terribly alarmed that the egg which she held in her hand fell into the basin. She got it out and washed the blood off, but in vain, it appeared again in a moment. She washed and scrubbed, but she could not get it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not long before the man came back from his journey, and the first things which he asked for were the key and the egg. She gave them to him, but she trembled as she did so, and he saw at once by the red spots that she had been in the bloody chamber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Since thou hast gone into the room against my will,” said he, “thou shalt go back into it against thine own. Thy life is ended.” He threw her down, dragged her thither by her hair, cut her head off on the block, and hewed her in pieces so that her blood ran on the ground. Then he threw her into the basin with the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Now I will fetch myself the second,” said the wizard, and again he went to the house in the shape of a poor man, and begged. Then the second daughter brought him a piece of bread; he caught her like the first, by simply touching her, and carried her away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She did not fare better than her sister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She allowed herself to be led away by her curiosity, opened the door of the bloody chamber, looked in, and had to atone for it with her life on the wizard’s return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he went and brought the third sister, but she was clever and crafty. When he had given her the keys and the egg, and had left her, she first put the egg away with great care, and then she examined the house, and at last went into the forbidden room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas, what did she behold!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both her sisters lay there in the basin, cruelly murdered, and cut in pieces. But she began to gather their limbs together and put them in order, head, body, arms and legs. And when nothing further was wanting the limbs began to move and unite themselves together, and both the maidens opened their eyes and were once more alive. Then they rejoiced and kissed and caressed each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On his arrival, the man at once demanded the keys and the egg, and as he could perceive no trace of any blood on it, he said, “Thou hast stood the test, thou shalt be my bride.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He now had no longer any power over her, and was forced to do whatsoever she desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, very well,” said she, “thou shalt first take a basketful of gold to my father and mother, and carry it thyself on thy back; in the meantime I will prepare for the wedding.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then she ran to her sisters, whom she had hidden in a little chamber, and said, “The moment has come when I can save you. The wretch shall himself carry you home again, but as soon as you are at home send help to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She put both of them in a basket and covered them quite over with gold, so that nothing of them was to be seen, then she called in the wizard and said to him, “Now carry the basket away, but I shall look through my little window and watch to see if thou stoppest on the way to stand or to rest.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wizard raised the basket on his back and went away with it, but it weighed him down so heavily that the perspiration streamed from his face. Then he sat down and wanted to rest awhile, but immediately one of the girls in the basket cried, “I am looking through my little window, and I see that thou art resting. Wilt thou go on at once?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He thought it was his bride who was calling that to him; and got up on his legs again. Once more he was going to sit down, but instantly she cried, “I am looking through my little window, and I see that thou art resting. Wilt thou go on directly?” And whenever he stood still, she cried this, and then he was forced to go onwards, until at last, groaning and out of breath, he took the basket with the gold and the two maidens into their parents’ house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At home, however, the bride prepared the marriage-feast, and sent invitations to the friends of the wizard. Then she took a skull with grinning teeth, put some ornaments on it and a wreath of flowers, carried it upstairs to the garret-window, and let it look out from thence. When all was ready, she got into a barrel of honey, and then cut the feather-bed open and rolled herself in it, until she looked like a wondrous bird, and no one could recognize her. Then she went out of the house, and on her way she met some of the wedding-guests, who asked,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“O, Fitcher’s bird, how com’st thou here?”&lt;br /&gt;
“I come from Fitcher’s house quite near.”&lt;br /&gt;
“And what may the young bride be doing?”&lt;br /&gt;
“From cellar to garret she’s swept all clean,&lt;br /&gt;
And now from the window she’s peeping, I ween.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last she met the bridegroom, who was coming slowly back. He, like the others, asked,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“O, Fitcher’s bird, how com’st thou here?”&lt;br /&gt;
“I come from Fitcher’s house quite near.”&lt;br /&gt;
“And what may the young bride be doing?&lt;br /&gt;
“From cellar to garret she’s swept all clean,&lt;br /&gt;
And now from the window she’s peeping, I ween.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bridegroom looked up, saw the decked-out skull, thought it was his bride, and nodded to her, greeting her kindly. But when he and his guests had all gone into the house, the brothers and kinsmen of the bride, who had been sent to rescue her, arrived. They locked all the doors of the house, that no one might escape, set fire to it, and the wizard and all his crew had to burn.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Evil Husbands &amp; Their Curious Wives -- Bluebeard.</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/bluebeard/"/>
		<updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/bluebeard/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first stop in our series, &amp;quot;Evil Husbands, and Their Curious Wives&amp;quot; features the classic tale of Bluebeard. This version is by Charles Perrault, as translated by Andrew Lang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bluebeard&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Bluebeard &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://myurl.com/bluebeard/#bluebeard&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was once a man who had fine houses, both in town and country, a deal of silver and gold plate, embroidered furniture, and coaches gilded all over with gold. But this man was so unlucky as to have a blue beard, which made him so frightfully ugly that all the women and girls ran away from him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of his neighbors, a lady of quality, had two daughters who were perfect beauties. He desired of her one of them in marriage, leaving to her choice which of the two she would bestow on him. Neither of them would have him, and they sent him backwards and forwards from one to the other, not being able to bear the thoughts of marrying a man who had a blue beard. Adding to their disgust and aversion was the fact that he already had been married to several wives, and nobody knew what had become of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blue Beard, to engage their affection, took them, with their mother and three or four ladies of their acquaintance, with other young people of the neighborhood, to one of his country houses, where they stayed a whole week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time was filled with parties, hunting, fishing, dancing, mirth, and feasting. Nobody went to bed, but all passed the night in rallying and joking with each other. In short, everything succeeded so well that the youngest daughter began to think that the man&#39;s beard was not so very blue after all, and that he was a mighty civil gentleman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as they returned home, the marriage was concluded. About a month afterwards, Blue Beard told his wife that he was obliged to take a country journey for six weeks at least, about affairs of very great consequence. He desired her to divert herself in his absence, to send for her friends and acquaintances, to take them into the country, if she pleased, and to make good cheer wherever she was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Here,&amp;quot; said he,&amp;quot; are the keys to the two great wardrobes, wherein I have my best furniture. These are to my silver and gold plate, which is not everyday in use. These open my strongboxes, which hold my money, both gold and silver; these my caskets of jewels. And this is the master key to all my apartments. But as for this little one here, it is the key to the closet at the end of the great hall on the ground floor. Open them all; go into each and every one of them, except that little closet, which I forbid you, and forbid it in such a manner that, if you happen to open it, you may expect my just anger and resentment.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She promised to observe, very exactly, whatever he had ordered. Then he, after having embraced her, got into his coach and proceeded on his journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her neighbors and good friends did not wait to be sent for by the newly married lady. They were impatient to see all the rich furniture of her house, and had not dared to come while her husband was there, because of his blue beard, which frightened them. They ran through all the rooms, closets, and wardrobes, which were all so fine and rich that they seemed to surpass one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, they went up into the two great rooms, which contained the best and richest furniture. They could not sufficiently admire the number and beauty of the tapestry, beds, couches, cabinets, stands, tables, and looking glasses, in which you might see yourself from head to foot; some of them were framed with glass, others with silver, plain and gilded, the finest and most magnificent that they had ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They ceased not to extol and envy the happiness of their friend, who in the meantime in no way diverted herself in looking upon all these rich things, because of the impatience she had to go and open the closet on the ground floor. She was so much pressed by her curiosity that, without considering that it was very uncivil for her to leave her company, she went down a little back staircase, and with such excessive haste that she nearly fell and broke her neck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having come to the closet door, she made a stop for some time, thinking about her husband&#39;s orders, and considering what unhappiness might attend her if she was disobedient; but the temptation was so strong that she could not overcome it. She then took the little key, and opened it, trembling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first she could not see anything plainly, because the windows were shut. After some moments she began to perceive that the floor was all covered over with clotted blood, on which lay the bodies of several dead women, ranged against the walls. (These were all the wives whom Blue Beard had married and murdered, one after another.) She thought she should have died for fear, and the key, which she, pulled out of the lock, fell out of her hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having somewhat recovered her surprise, she picked up the key, locked the door, and went upstairs into her chamber to recover; but she could not, so much was she frightened. Having observed that the key to the closet was stained with blood, she tried two or three times to wipe it off; but the blood would not come out; in vain did she wash it, and even rub it with soap and sand. The blood still remained, for the key was magical and she could never make it quite clean; when the blood was gone off from one side, it came again on the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blue Beard returned from his journey the same evening, saying that he had received letters upon the road, informing him that the affair he went about had concluded to his advantage. His wife did all she could to convince him that she was extremely happy about his speedy return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning he asked her for the keys, which she gave him, but with such a trembling hand that he easily guessed what had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What!&amp;quot; said he, &amp;quot;is not the key of my closet among the rest?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I must,&amp;quot; said she, &amp;quot;have left it upstairs upon the table.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Fail not,&amp;quot; said Blue Beard, &amp;quot;to bring it to me at once.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After several goings backwards and forwards, she was forced to bring him the key. Blue Beard, having very attentively considered it, said to his wife, &amp;quot;Why is there blood on the key?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I do not know,&amp;quot; cried the poor woman, paler than death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You do not know!&amp;quot; replied Blue Beard. &amp;quot;I very well know. You went into the closet, did you not? Very well, madam; you shall go back, and take your place among the ladies you saw there.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon this she threw herself at her husband&#39;s feet, and begged his pardon with all the signs of a true repentance, vowing that she would never more be disobedient. She would have melted a rock, so beautiful and sorrowful was she; but Blue Beard had a heart harder than any rock!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You must die, madam,&amp;quot; said he, &amp;quot;at once.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Since I must die,&amp;quot; answered she (looking upon him with her eyes all bathed in tears), &amp;quot;give me some little time to say my prayers.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I give you,&amp;quot; replied Blue Beard, &amp;quot;half a quarter of an hour, but not one moment more.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she was alone she called out to her sister, and said to her, &amp;quot;Sister Anne&amp;quot; (for that was her name), &amp;quot;go up, I beg you, to the top of the tower, and look if my brothers are not coming. They promised me that they would come today, and if you see them, give them a sign to make haste.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her sister Anne went up to the top of the tower, and the poor afflicted wife cried out from time to time, &amp;quot;Anne, sister Anne, do you see anyone coming?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And sister Anne said, &amp;quot;I see nothing but a cloud of dust in the sun, and the green grass.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meanwhile Blue Beard, holding a great saber in his hand, cried out as loud as he could bawl to his wife, &amp;quot;Come down instantly, or I shall come up to you.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;One moment longer, if you please,&amp;quot; said his wife; and then she cried out very softly, &amp;quot;Anne, sister Anne, do you see anybody coming?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And sister Anne answered, &amp;quot;I see nothing but a cloud of dust in the sun, and the green grass.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Come down quickly,&amp;quot; cried Blue Beard, &amp;quot;or I will come up to you.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I am coming,&amp;quot; answered his wife; and then she cried, &amp;quot;Anne, sister Anne, do you not see anyone coming?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I see,&amp;quot; replied sister Anne, &amp;quot;a great cloud of dust approaching us.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Are they my brothers?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Alas, no my dear sister, I see a flock of sheep.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Will you not come down?&amp;quot; cried Blue Beard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;One moment longer,&amp;quot; said his wife, and then she cried out, &amp;quot;Anne, sister Anne, do you see nobody coming?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I see,&amp;quot; said she, &amp;quot;two horsemen, but they are still a great way off.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;God be praised,&amp;quot; replied the poor wife joyfully. &amp;quot;They are my brothers. I will make them a sign, as well as I can for them to make haste.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Blue Beard bawled out so loud that he made the whole house tremble. The distressed wife came down, and threw herself at his feet, all in tears, with her hair about her shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This means nothing,&amp;quot; said Blue Beard. &amp;quot;You must die!&amp;quot; Then, taking hold of her hair with one hand, and lifting up the sword with the other, he prepared to strike off her head. The poor lady, turning about to him, and looking at him with dying eyes, desired him to afford her one little moment to recollect herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;No, no,&amp;quot; said he, &amp;quot;commend yourself to God,&amp;quot; and was just ready to strike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this very instant there was such a loud knocking at the gate that Blue Beard made a sudden stop. The gate was opened, and two horsemen entered. Drawing their swords, they ran directly to Blue Beard. He knew them to be his wife&#39;s brothers, one a dragoon, the other a musketeer; so that he ran away immediately to save himself; but the two brothers pursued and overtook him before he could get to the steps of the porch. Then they ran their swords through his body and left him dead. The poor wife was almost as dead as her husband, and had not strength enough to rise and welcome her brothers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blue Beard had no heirs, and so his wife became mistress of all his estate. She made use of one part of it to marry her sister Anne to a young gentleman who had loved her a long while; another part to buy captains&#39; commissions for her brothers, and the rest to marry herself to a very worthy gentleman, who made her forget the ill time she had passed with Blue Beard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: https://sites.pitt.edu/~dash/perrault03.html&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
